ENRIQUE SANTIBÁÑEZ CORTÉS

LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/3lhCsI2, Github: https://bit.ly/3BTm5Y6

I am a recent graduate of my master's degree, wanting to learn more every day. With two year of experience as a Data Scientist. I have extra computer knowledge with the help of the online platform Coursera, DataCamp and EDX with more than 40 scientific events with topics related to Statistics, Mathematics and/or Computation.

WORK HISTORY

JULY 2022-PRESENT

DATA SCIENTIST EXPERT, BBVA

Project for the detection of time series with unusual behavior, determining confidence intervals for the prediction of the following month. The model that obtained the best results (performance metric and computational time) was an RRN. The final product was a dashboard showing all the product combinations, with their respective time series and a list of alerts.

JANUARY 2022-JULY 2022

INTERNSHIP MASTER, KANTAR

Considering the NBD-Dirichlet model which is a mixture of 4-phase distributions, analyze the consumer's purchasing behavior, focusing on studying the value of brands.

SEPTEMBER 2019-AUGUST 2020

DATA SCIENCE, OPI ANALYTICS

Opi Analytics is a Mexican company that develops technological tools for data analysis for decision-making. During the work period I have built ETLs, analyze different sources of information to make sales predictions, estimate the effect caused by different events (new launches, promotions, etc.), and make geographical indicators.

JUNE, 2019 - AUGUST, 2019

INVESTIGATOR, INSTITUTE OF SOCIAL INVESTIGATIONS, UNAM.

Incorporated in one of the current research projects of Dr. Judith Zubieta García, in which her knowledge of Statistics was used to conclude the analysis of the information

EDUCATION

AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

MASTER'S DEGREE IN STATISTICAL COMPUTING, CENTER FOR RESEARCH IN MATHEMATICS, MEXICO.

Thesis: BO-TextAutoAugment Data augmentation automatic in NLP using Bayesian Optimization. Assistant in two master's courses related to Data Science.

2015-2019

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: STATISTICS, AUTONOMOUS UNIVERSITY OF CHAPINGO

Thesis: Estimation of Mexico's income using Phase-Type distributions.

APTITUDES

- Strong knowledge of statistics and deep learning (DEL, NLP).
- Advanced/intermediate programming, R and Python.
- Work experience: PBI, Amazon platform (EC2), Azure (Data Bricks, Data Factory), Spark (pyspark), Git and use of Docker containers.
- Office y LaTeX.
- Eager to learn, initiative.

PARTICIPATIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS (LAST 3 YEARS)

- 1. 15° Industrial Problem Solving Workshop, CIMAT. (2022)
- 2. Winner of the SAS LATAM 2021 scholarship, SAS Institute. (2021)
- 3. 14° Industrial Problem Solving Workshop, CIMAT. (2021)
- 4. XIX School of Probability, and Statistics, CIMAT. (2021)
- 5. Mexican workshop on data science and big data, CIMAT. (2020)
- 6. 1st School of Distributed Algorithms and Parallel Algorithms, CIMAT. (2020)
- 7. Summer School Natural Language Processing (2020).
- 8. Summer of scientific research, AMC. (2019)
- 9. XVII School of Probability, and Statistics, CIMAT. (2019)
- 10. Workshop on inference and quantification of uncertainty in problems in science and engineering, UNAM. (2019)

CERTIFICATIONS

EDX

• MICROMASTER OF STATISTICS AND DATA SCIENCE 40% (2 CURSOS)

DATACAMP

- PYTHON PROGRAMMER 100% (15 CURSOS)
- DATA ANALYST WITH PYTHON 100% (6 CURSOS)
- MACHINE LEARNING SCIENTIST WITH PYTHON 23% (3 CURSOS)
- BIG DATA WITH PYTHON 86% (5 CURSOS)
- DATA ANALYST WITH R 58% (13 CURSOS)

COURSERA

SPECIALIZATION:

- Python for everyone 60% (3 cursos)
- Introduction to Data Science 75% (3 cursos)
- Practical Predictive Analytics: Models and Methods, online Coursera. (2021)
- Bayesian Statistics: From Concept to Data Analysis, online Coursera. (2020)
- Neutral Networks and Deep Learning. Deeplearning, online Coursera. (2019)
- Python for Data Science. International Business Machines (IBM), online Coursera. (2018)
- Introduction to Data Science in Python. University of Michigan, online Coursera. (2018)